Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.21
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Dick Thornburgh Papers, Series XXI. Scrapbooks
1966-1987
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Thornburgh, Dick
AIS.1998.30.21
35 items
The Dick Thornburgh scrapbook collection, consists of 25 linear feet of colorful material. Family members started collecting news articles and clippings in the 1960s, early in his career, when Dick Thornburgh was just launching into civic activity and political participation. His wife, Ginny, was a dedicated "scrapbook maker" and the results of her efforts are an excellent record of Thornburgh's early years up until the 1978 gubernatorial campaign, when campaign staff essentially took over the task. There are nine oversized scrapbooks from the 1978 and 1982 campaigns for Governor that include some material not found elsewhere in the collection. All of the above have been reformatted for preservation. Other family members contributed more family and notable event oriented scrapbooks. Although preservation concerns remain for some of these, they add significant color and content to the Dick Thornburgh archives. Digital reproductions of portions of the collection are available online.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dick Thornburgh, February 27, 1998.
Previous Citation
Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932-, AIS.1998.30, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Government; Women; Politics; Personal papers; Education; Social action; Pennsylvania -- Politics and government -- 1951-; Political campaigns -- Pennsylvania; United States. Office of the Assistant Attorney General; Pennsylvania. Constitutional Convention (1967-1968); United States. Attorney (Pennsylvania: Western District); United States. Congress. House -- Elections; Pennsylvania. Governor -- Elections; Pennsylvania. Governor (1979-1987: Thornburgh); Thornburgh family; Thornburgh, Ginny (Judson); Thornburgh, Dick
- Scrapbooks, 1966-1987; XXI.
  Scope and Contents note
  It is not unusual for collections of public figures to include scrapbooks. The archives of Dick Thornburgh are no exception. Family members, in particular, started collecting news articles and clippings in the 1960s, early in his career when Thornburgh was just launching into civic activity and political participation. His wife, Ginny, was a dedicated "scrapbook maker" and the results of her efforts are an excellent record of Thornburgh's early years up until the 1978 gubernatorial campaign, when campaign staff essentially took over the task. Ginny's early scrapbooks have all been reformatted for preservation and are incredibly useful. When she started out in the early 1960s there was no way to know that she was documenting the foundations of such a remarkable public service career as Dick Thornburgh's became in subsequent years.
  In addition, there are oversized scrapbooks from both the 1978 and 1982 campaigns for Governor, 9 in total. They are a fascinating account of the ups and downs of the 1978 campaign against former Pittsburgh Mayor, Peter Flaherty, as well as the 1982 re-election campaign against Alan Ertel. Anyone exploring the changes in campaigns over the years, as well as the issue content of each, will find these very interesting. These, too, have been reformatted for preservation.
  Ginny Thornburgh's mother, Virginia Judson, and Dick Thornburgh's sister, Ann Thornburgh also contributed charming scrapbooks about Ginny's public life, and Thornburgh family oriented inaugural scrapbooks, as well as other notable events. Nowhere is the affection of the Thornburgh family better represented. Although preservation concerns remain for some of these, these scrapbooks add significant color and content to the Dick Thornburgh archives.
  - Dick Thornburgh Scrapbooks, 1.
    - Newsclippings Vols.I-IX, 1966-1978
      - Volume I: includes Campaign for U.S. Congress, 1966, and Constitutional Convention, 1967-1968, 1966-1968 (Box SB1, Item 1)
      - Volume II: includes selection as U.S. Attorney for Western Pennsylvania, 1969, 1969-1970 (Box SB1, Item 2)
      - Volume III: U.S.Attorney, 1970 (Box SB1, Item 3)
      - Volume IV: U.S. Attorney, 1971-1972 (Box SB2, Item 1)
      - Volume V: U.S. Attorney, November 1972-1973 (Box SB2, Item 2)
      - Volume VI: includes appointment as Assistant Attorney General, Criminal Division, January 1974-May, 1975 (Box SB2, Item 3)
      - Volume VII: Assistant Attorney General, Criminal Division, May-December 1975 (Box SB3, Item 1)
      - Volume VIII: Assistant Attorney General, Criminal Division, January-July 1976 (Box SB3, Item 2)
      - Volume IX: Concludes with resignation as Assistant Attorney General and return to Pittsburgh, August 1976-March, 1977 (Box SB3, Item 3)
    - Ann Thornburgh Scrapbooks, 1966-1978, 1988
      - U.S. Congress Campaign through Assistant Attorney General, Washington, DC, 1966-1976 (Box SB3, Item 4)
      - Thornburgh named Attorney General of the United States, 1988 (Box SB3, Item 5)
  - Campaigns for Governor, 2.
    - Campaign for Governor, 1978
      - Volume I: Pre primary up to and including Campaign Announcement, January, 1978, 1977-Spring 1978 (Box SB4, Item 1)
      - Volume II: Primary Election, Spring 1978-May 1978 (Box SB5, Item 2)
      - Volume III: Post Primary and General Election Campaign, June-September 1978 (Box SB6, Item 1)
      - Volume IV: General Election Campaign, October-November 1978 (Box SB7, Item 2)
      - Volume V: Election Day and Transition, November 1978-February 1979 (Box SB8, Item 1)
    - Re-election Campaign for Governor (with reformats), 1982
      - Volume I: Primary Campaign; and reformatted scrapbook, September 1981-May 1982 (Box SB9, Item 1)
      - Volume II: General Election Campaign; and reformatted scrapbook, May-August 1982 (Box SB10, Item 2)
      - Volume III: General Election Campaign - Election Day; and reformatted scrapbook, September-November 7,1982 (Box SB11, Item 1)
      - Volume IV: Victory - Inauguration; and reformatted scrapbook, November 8, 1982 -January, 1983 (Box SB12, Item 2)
  - Ginny Thornburgh Scrapbooks, 3.
    - Gubernatorial Campaign '78 (1 of 2), 1978 (Box SB13, Item 1)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign '78 (2 of 2), 1978 (Box SB13, Item 2)
    - Inaugural (1 of 2), 1979 (Box SB13, Item 3)
    - Inaugural (2 of 2), 1979 (Box SB13, Item 4)
    - Virginia Judson (Ginny's mother) Scrapbook of Europe trip, 1973 (Box SB13, Item 5)
    - Ann Thornburgh (sister of Dick Thornburgh) scrapbook about Ginny Thornburgh, 1963-1975 (Box SB13, Item 6)
  - Scrapbooks, 1980-1987; 4.
    - News clippings and ephemera, Spring-August, 1980 (Box SB14, Item 1)
    - News clippings and ephemera, September-December, 1980 (Box SB14, Item 2)
    - News clippings and ephemera, late 1980-1981 (Box SB14, Item 3)
    - News clippings and ephemera, January-November, 1981 (Box SB14, Item 4)
    - News clippings and ephemera, May-June 1982 (Box SB14, Item 5)
    - News clippings and ephemera, September - November 1982 (Box SB14, Item 6)
    - News clippings and ephemera, January-May 1983 (Box SB15, Item 1)
    - News clippings and ephemera, May-December 1983 (Box SB15, Item 2)
    - News clippings and ephemera, 1984-1987 (Box SB15, Item 3)
  - Reformatted Scrapbooks, 5.
    - Newsclippings Vols.I-IX, 1966-1978
      - Reformat SB Vol. 1, 1966-1968 (Box SB16, Item 1)
      - Reformat SB Vol. 2, 1969-1970 (Box SB16, Item 2)
      - Reformat SB Vol. 3, 1970 (Box SB16, Item 3)
      - Reformat SB Vol. 4, 1971-1972 (Box SB16, Item 4)
      - Reformat SB Vol. 5, November 1972-1973 (Box SB16, Item 5)
      - Reformat SB Vol. 6, January 1974-May, 1975 (Box SB17, Item 1)
      - Reformat SB Vol. 7, May-December 1975 (Box SB17, Item 2)
      - Reformat SB Vol. 8, January-July 1976 (Box SB17, Item 3)
      - Reformat SB Vol. 9, August 1976-March, 1977 (Box SB17, Item 4)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1978
      - 78 Reformatted Scrapbooks I, 1977-Spring 1978 (Box SB18, Item 1)
      - 78 Reformatted Scrapbook II, Spring 1978-May 1978 (Box SB18, Item 2)
      - 78 Reformatted Scrapbooks III, June-September 1978 (Box SB19, Item 1)
      - 78 Reformatted Scrapbook IV, October-November 1978 (Box SB19, Item 2)
      - 78 Reformatted Scrapbook V, November 1978-February 1979 (Box SB20, Item 1)